PHD CANDIDATE · DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, HKUST, HK

Robotics Institute, CYT Building, HKUST, Clear Water Bay, HK

□ (+852) 609-44-786 | 💌 usmanmaqbool@outlook.com | # usmanmaqbool.github.io | 🖸 UsmanMaqbool | 🛅 usmanmaqbool



"Be so good they can't ignore you."

Summary.

This is M Usman Maqbool Bhutta. I'm PhD candidate at (Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab) HKUST. My PhD primary research is on multi-agent SLAM system and the expected graduation (\sim Mar. 2021). I developed multi-agent direct SLAM systems triggered by first loop-closure matching (see my publication section). Furthermore, I'm currently working for a better and lightweight place recognition techniques using machine learning. I'm Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. I've 7+ years of experience specializing in robotics R&D and project management. I previously owned an IT company, and I've part of several startups since 2011. My full profile can view here (https://usmanmaqbool.github.io/).

Work Experience [7+ Years]

RESEARCH

Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, Robotics Institute

HKUST, HK

PHD CANDIDATE Sep 2016 - Present

- PhD Supervisor: Prof Ming Liu, Director of Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab (RAM-LAB)
- Research in SLAM: I've worked mainly for the multi-agent SLAM system. To find the scale difference and excellent relative transformation between difference agents. I've produced PCR-Pro work. This work got best student paper finalist award at IEEE-CYBER 2018.
- Research in Automation: For smartphone glass inspection, I've introduced Smart-Inspect work. This work is accepted in IROS 2020. The patent is also under-review in the US.

Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL)

ETH Zürich, Switzerland.

ACADEMIC GUEST

Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2020

- Supervisor: Prof. Roland Siegwart, Director of Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL), ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- · Co-Supervisor: Dr. Cesar Dario Cadena Lerma, Senior Researcher at ASL, ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- Research in Machine Learning: I've worked for making the better place recognition for SLAM systems. Furthermore, I've also introduced light weight representation of key-frames for better channel utilization.

Department of Electronics

QAU, Pakistan Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

• M.Phil. Supervisor: **Prof Hasan Mahmood**, Department of Electronics, QAU. Research in Image Processing (CNN): I've introduced CNN-based license plate recognition of Pakistani's Cars. This work has been published in IEEE-ICALIP 2014.

INDUSTRY AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP

Lisee Technology Corporation Limited

Central HK Jan 2018 - Present

- Won funding support for company | TSSSU Support HK\$ 300,000 (Jun 19 - May 20).

- Indoor Navigation for Libray using Lisee Technology | PCF Support HK\$ 160,000 (Jun 18 - May 19).

Friends Corporate Technologies

Islamabad, PK

Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

Federal Government of Pakistan

Islamabad. PK

May 2012 - Feb 2013

Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

Server4Sale, LLC

Islamabad. PK Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

ACADEMIC

PHP DEVELOPER

Department of Computer Science

BZU-Sahiwal. Pakistan

LECTURER (VISITING) Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

BHUTTA, M USMAN MAOBOOL · RÉSUMÉ

SEPTEMBER 22, 2020

Department of Physics GPGC Sahiwal, Pakistan

Tarabina DC alausia (Flantas dia nalata) anno 11 alaus Dusianta)

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

Department of Electronics

QAU, Pakistan

Aug. 2015 - Apr. 2016

 Instructer
 Aug. 2010 - Dec. 2010

'PHP Web Development' (a short course) offered in Department of Electronics, Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan.

Presentation

IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems [IROS, 2020]

Las Vegas, USA

PRESENTOR AS AUTHOR

Oct. 2020

• Introduced Smart-Inspect for the micro scale localization and classification of smartphone glass defects for industrial automation.

Technology Start-up Support Scheme for Universities (TSSSU)

HKUST, Hong Kong

PRESENTER AS COO LISEE TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION COMPANY LIMITED, HONG KONG.

Jan. 2019

• Introduced Lisee technology in front of selection committee panel and won TSSSU 2019-20 funding of the amount of HK\$300,000.

IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems [IEEE-CYBER 2018]

Tianjin, China

PRESENTOR AS AUTHOR Jul. 2018

• Introduced PCR-Pro for the estimation of information matrix and scale difference for pose graph SLAM.

IET-Young Professionals Exhibition and Competition (IET-YPEC) 2018

CityU, Hong Kong

PRESENTER AS COO LISEE TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION COMPANY LIMITED, HONG KONG.

Jul. 2018

Introduced Lisee technology at IET-YPEC 2018.

Campus Challenge @ HKUST Transportation

HKUST, Hong Kong

PRESENTER AS PARTICIPENT May 2018

HKUST got 80+ proposals for this compeitions, and arranged a roadshow. My proposal got selected for the audiance award after getting maximum votes.

High Tech Innovation and Entrepreneurship

HKUST, Hong Kong

PRESENTER AS ENTREPRENEUR

Dec. 2017

· Introduced my study related to the flying cars.

World First Youth Robotics Developemnt Forum 2017

Shangri-La Shenzhen, China.

Presenter as author.

Nov. 2017

- Introduced my work related to multi-agent SLAM system.

Education

Ph.D. Candidate in Robotics at RAM-LAB, Robotics Institute

HKUST, Hong Kong

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC & COMPUTER ENGINEERING, THE HONG KONG UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

Sep. 2016 - ~Feb. 2021

- PhD Supervisor: Prof Ming Liu, Director of Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab (RAM-LAB)
- Exchange Supervisor: Prof. Roland Siegwart, Director of Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL), ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- Exchange Co-Supervisor: **Dr. Cesar Dario Cadena Lerma**, Senior Researcher at ASL, **ETH Zürich**, Switzerland.
- Got PEEF CCMS PhD scholarship from Pakistan and overseas research award (ORA).
- · Research: Multi-Agent SLAM System, Place Recognition, Autonomous Car and Deep Learning for automation industry.

M.Phil. in Electronics QAU, Pakistan

Department of Electronics, Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan.

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- M.Phil. Supervisor: Prof Hasan Mahmood, Department of Electronics, QAU.
- Research: Signal and Image Processing
- Grade: A

M.Sc. in Electronics QAU, Pakistan

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS, QUAID-I-AZAM UNIVERSITY, ISLAMABAD, PAKISTAN.

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

• 2nd position in batch

• Projects: completed 9+ projects related to C++, Verilog/HDL and Micro-controller programming.

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Physics

BZU, Pakistan

Bahauddin Zakariya University, Multan Pakistan

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

· Grade: 1st Division

Honors & Awards INTERNATIONAL Best Student Paper Finalist Award, IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Tianjin, China Intelligent Systems May, 2018 Audience Award, Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST HKUST, HK Shenzhen, China Nov, 2017 Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST May, 2017 Completion Award, The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST HKUST, HK Dec, 2016 Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST Shenzhen, China Nov, 2016 Completion Award, Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus HKUST, HK DOMESTIC CCMS PhD Scholarship, Won Chief Minister Marit Scholarship (CCMS) scholarship award by Punjab Sep 2016 Lahore, PK Government (PEEF), Pakistan for pursuing my PhD studies at HKUST, HK Sep 2013 Participant, Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative Islamabad, PK Apr 2013 Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition Islamabad, PK Apr 2013 Participant, Case EPICA Islamabad, PK Apr 2013 Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan Islamabad, PK Oct 2012 Participant, Punjab Youth Festival Lahore, PK Oct 2011 Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival Islamabad, PK Sep 2011 Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival Lahore, PK Apr 2011 Completion Award, Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan Islamabad, PK Dec 2011 Participant, National Drama Festival Islamabad, PK

Academic Activities

IROS	Referee Service , IEEE/RSJ RA-L and International Conference on Robotics and Automation	2020
Spr 2020	Teaching Assistant , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
ICRA	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Robotics and Automation	2020
Spr 2019	Teaching Assistant , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
CASE	Referee Service, IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering	2019
IROS	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	2019, 2018
Fall 2018	Teaching Assistant, ELEC4820 - Medical Imaging	HKUST, HK
Spr 2018	Teaching Assistant , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
Spr 2017	Teaching Assistant , ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK

Research Publications

Loop-box: Multi-Agent Direct SLAM Triggered by Single Loop Closure for Large Scale Mapping

Dec 2010 Instuctor of short Course, PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU

Apr 2013 Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan

Dec 2008 Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU

Apr 2013 Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club

Journal Paper

Islamabad, PK

Mansehra, PK

Islamabad, PK

Islamabad, PK

M Usman Maqbool Bhutta*, Manohar Kuse, Rui Fan, Yanan Liu, Ming Liu IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics (IF: 11+)

Oct 2020

Smart-Inspect: Micro Scale Localization and Classification of Smart Phone Glass Defects for Industrial Automation

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA*, SHOAIB ASLAM, PENG YUN, JIANHAO JIAO, MING LIU IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS 2020)

Oct 2020

Multiple Lane Detection Algorithm Based on Optimised Dense Disparity Map Estimation

Conference Paper

Han Ma, Yixin Ma, Jianhao Jiao, M Usman Maqbool Bhutta, Mohammud Junaid Bocus, Lujia Wang, Ming Liu, Rui Fan Accepted in IEEE International Conference on Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST 2018)

Oct 2018

PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Conference Paper

M Usman Maqbool Bhutta*, Ming Liu

Jul 2018

Presented in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems (IEEE-CYBER 2018), and won Best Student Paper Finalist Award.

An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA*, HASAN MAHMOOD, AND HAROON MALIK

Jul 2014

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP 2014).

Efficient Reset Design Techniques

QAMAR, ZOHA, BUSHRA YASEEN, AND USMAN MAQBOOL

Journal Paper

Published in Science International Lahore